I'll give you one
سأعطيك واحدة
or two taels,
أو اثنين من التيل ،
I'll give you 3 liang.
سأعطيك 3 ليانغ.
I'll give you 4 taels,
سأعطيك 4 تايل ،
Du Mao will say the same thing,
سيقول "دو ماو" نفس الشيء ،
These slaves are five taels of silver each.
هؤلاء العبيد هم خمسة تيل من الفضة لكل منهم.
If you want it, hurry up.
إذا كنت تريد ذلك ، أسرع.
Official Du is frank.
دو الرسمية صريحة.
I'll buy ten.
سأشتري عشرة.
Okay,
تمام،
Bring those soldiers surnamed Liu here.
أحضر هؤلاء الجنود ولقبهم ليو هنا.
These army slaves want
هؤلاء عبيد الجيش يريدون
10 taels of silver. Hurry up,
10 تايل من الفضة.  أسرع - بسرعة،
It turns out that these slaves can be bought and sold,
اتضح أن هؤلاء العبيد يمكن شراؤهم وبيعهم ،
so that's easy to deal with.
لذلك من السهل التعامل معها.
All our savings
كل مدخراتنا
have been redeemed by Miss Liu.
تم استبدالها من قبل الآنسة ليو.
What should we do?
ماذا علينا ان نفعل؟
There are only a few left.
لم يتبق سوى عدد قليل.
Why would I lie to you?
لماذا اكذب عليك؟
Do you think the boss can't find you
هل تعتقد أن الرئيس لا يستطيع العثور عليك
if you hide it?
إذا قمت بإخفائها؟
Childish.
طفولي.
These slaves will be charged at 10 liang each,
سيتم فرض رسوم على هؤلاء العبيد 10 ليانغ لكل منهم ،
so hurry up if you want them.
لذلك أسرع إذا كنت تريدهم.
Mr. Du,
السيد أنت ،
I'll take all these slaves.
سآخذ كل هؤلاء العبيد.
All of them.
كل منهم.
Do you know that there are as many as 100 soldiers?
هل تعلم أن هناك ما يصل إلى 100 جندي؟
I want to be frank
اريد ان اكون صريحا
with 100 people,
مع 100 شخص ،
I, Du Mao, stand by your words. Wait
أنا ، دو ماو ، أقف إلى جانب كلماتك.  انتظر
a minute.
دقيقة.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
There's no one who doesn't bargain in business.
لا يوجد أحد لا يساوم في العمل.
Do you want it?
هل تريده؟
Yes,
نعم،
I still want it.
ما زلت أريده.
This business is about honest trading,
يتعلق هذا العمل بالتداول الصادق ،
Mr. Du,
السيد أنت ،
What about us?
ماذا عنا؟
I wanted to establish
كنت أرغب في إنشاء
a long-term partnership with you.
شراكة طويلة الأمد معك.
But,
لكن،
look at you, army slaves,
انظروا إليكم ، عبيد الجيش ،
Hey,
يا،
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
Look at how strong this man is,
انظر إلى مدى قوة هذا الرجل ،
Is there a problem?
هل هناك مشكلة؟
How much rice do you have to eat in a day?
ما هي كمية الأرز التي يجب أن تأكلها في اليوم؟
What should we do if we eat our family poor?
ماذا نفعل إذا أكلنا عائلتنا الفقيرة؟
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
She's so handsome,
انها وسيمه جدا
how can my maid work with peace of mind?
كيف يمكن لخادمي العمل براحة البال؟
Hey,
يا،
This is too much.
هذا كثير للغاية.
What kind of person do you think this is?
أي نوع من الأشخاص تعتقد هذا؟
Pretending to be a good fish-eye,
يتظاهر بأنه عين سمكة جيدة ،
will he serve me or should I serve him?
هل يخدمني أم أخدمه؟
Am I right?
هل انا على حق؟
Isn't it too much for a guy like this
أليس هذا كثيرًا بالنسبة لرجل مثل هذا
to be 10 liang each?
أن تكون 10 ليانغ لكل منهما؟
Oh,
أوه،
we bought so many,
اشترينا الكثير ،
Give me a 30% discount.
أعطني خصم 30٪.
After hearing what you said,
بعد سماع ما قلته ،
it makes some sense.
من المنطقي.
Okay,
تمام،
I, Du Mao, stand by my words,
أنا ، دو ماو ، أقف بجانب كلماتي ،
Then.
ثم.
This is ridiculous.
هذا سخيف.
The Liu family is the descendant of the Seven Generations'Generals, and
عائلة ليو هي من نسل جنرالات الأجيال السبعة ، و
our ancestors have the merit of following the dragon.
أسلافنا لديهم ميزة اتباع التنين.
If you are invincible on the battlefield,
إذا كنت لا تقهر في ساحة المعركة ،
how can you be reduced
كيف يمكن تقليلها
to a bargain sale?
لبيع صفقة؟
Ten taels of silver
عشرة تايل من الفضة
and a 30% discount.
وخصم 30٪.
I might as well kill myself here.
قد أقتل نفسي هنا.
Even if you sell it,
حتى لو قمت ببيعها ،
it will cost at least 50 taels each.
سيكلف ما لا يقل عن 50 تيل لكل منهما.
That's right.
صحيح.
50 taels,
50 تيل ،
You can even raise your own price.
يمكنك حتى رفع السعر الخاص بك.
Okay,
تمام،
I, Du Mao, said no, no, no,
أنا ، دو ماو ، قلت لا ، لا ، لا ،
no, no, no, no, no, no Shi 50 taels each with a total price of 5. 2
لا ، لا ، لا ، لا ، لا ، لا شي 50 تايل لكل منها بسعر إجمالي 5. 2
thousand.
ألف.
You really have business acumen
لديك حقًا فطنة في مجال الأعمال
to make us pay five times more out of thin air.
لجعلنا ندفع خمس مرات أكثر من فراغ.
Du Mao, given seven days,
دو ماو ، سبعة أيام ،
we can find a way
يمكننا إيجاد طريقة
to raise the 5. 2 thousand
لرفع 5. 2 آلاف
after drinking this bowl of porridge.
بعد شرب هذا الوعاء من العصيدة.
Sir,
سيد،
two more plates of good shredded pickles,
طبقان آخران من المخللات المبشورة الجيدة ،
Okay, I'll be right there.
حسنًا ، سأكون هناك.